A Finding Aid to the Allen Tupper True and True Family Papers, 1841-1987, in the Archives of American Art AAA.truealle
Archives of American Art
Allen Tupper True and True family papers
1841-1987
AAA.truealle
Archives of American Art
8.2 Linear feet
The Allen Tupper True and True family papers date from 1841 to 1987 and measure 8.2 linear feet. The collection presents a good overview of True's personal life and and his career as mural painter and illustrator specializing in Western themes.
Allen Tupper True and True family
Biographical Note
Allen Tupper True (1881-1955) was born in Colorado Springs, Colorado in 1881. He was a student at the University of Denver, and studied at the Corcoran School of Art, Washington, D.C. between 1901 and 1902. In 1902, he was accepted into Howard Pyle's classes in Chadd's Ford, Pennsylvania, and studied there until 1908, befriending classmates George Harding, Gordon McCouch, Thornton Oakley, and N.C. Wyeth. Through Pyle, True began his career as a magazine illustrator.
From approximately 1913-1915, True worked with British muralist Frank Brangwyn, assisting Brangwyn in the execution of murals at the Panama-Pacific Exposition in San Francisco, California.
After marrying Emma Goodman Eaton in 1915 (divorced 1934), True launched his career as a mural painter. His most notable works include the mural decorations in the state capitol buildings of Colorado, Missouri, Nebraska, and Wyoming, as well as murals for the Mountain States Telephone and Telegraph Company Building and the Civic Center in Denver, Colorado. True specialized in depicting Western and Native American themes.
From 1934-1945, True acted as consultant for the U.S. Bureau of Reclamation, in charge of and designing all decoration and color schemes for the Boulder Dam power plant, Grand Coulee Dam, and the Shasta Dam, among others.
True was a Unitarian Mason, and a member of the Mural Painters of America, Beta Theta Pi, Cactus Club of Denver, and the Author's Club, London. He died in 1955.
Scope and Content Note
The Allen Tupper True and True family papers date from 1841 to 1987 and measure 8.2 linear feet. The collection presents a good overview of True's personal life and and his career as mural painter and illustrator specializing in Western themes. Through art work, project files, photographs, and printed material, the collection offers a rich resource, both textually and visually of True's research and work on documenting early twentieth century Native Americans cultural traditions. The papers also document True's childhood and his relationship with his family through various family papers, such as correspondence, genealogies, subject files, photographs, and a scrapbook. The collection is a particularly rich resource for the study of Allen Tupper True's work, as well as original documentation of the American West and Native American culture.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into thirteen series according to material type. The contents of each series have been arranged chronologically. Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers.
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1895-1964, undated (box 1, 7 folders)
Series 2: Subject Files, 1873-1955 (box 1, 16 folders)
Series 3: Correspondence, 1841-1956 (boxes 1-4, 3.5 linear ft.)
Series 4: Business Records, 1903-1951 (box 4, 4 folders)
Series 5: Notes, 1902-1920 (box 5, 10 folders)
Series 6: Writings, 1896-1926 (box 5, 5 folders)
Series 7: Artwork, 1897-1923 (boxes 5, 10, and OV folder, 0.5 linear ft.)
Series 8: Project Files, 1912-1987 (box 5, 0.75 linear ft.)
Series 9: Photographs, 1859-1950 (boxes 6-7, 1.5 linear ft.)
Series 10: Scrapbook, 1934 (box 7, 1 volume)
Series 11: Printed Material, 1875-1981 (box 7, 20 folders)
Series 12: Artifacts, ca. 1863 (box 10, 9 items)
Series 13: Glass Plate Negatives, undated (boxes 8-9, 0.8 linear ft.)
Provenance
The Allen Tupper True and True family papers were donated in February and April 1988 by True's daughter Jane True Mueller and his son, Frank True.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Patrons must use microfilm copy. Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers.
Alternative Forms Available
The collection is available on microfilm reels 4891-4898. The microfilm is available for interlibrary loan.
Borglum, Gutzon, 1867-1941; Brangwyn, Frank, Sir, 1867-1956; Pyle, Howard, 1853-1911; Wyeth, N. C. (Newell Convers), 1882-1945; Artists' studios--Photographs; Cartoons (working drawings); Christmas cards; Diaries; Drawings; Illustrated letters; Illustrators--Colorado--Denver; Indians of North America--Portraits; Mural painting and decoration, American; Muralists--Colorado--Denver; Photographs; Sketchbooks; Sketches; Works of art
- Biographical Material, 1895-1964, undated; Series 1; (box 1, 7 folders)
  Scope and Contents note
  This series includes family genealogies, biographical accounts, passports, school papers, an award medal for horsemanship, membership cards, and copies of True's will.
  - True family genealogies, 1964, undated (Box 1, Reel 4891)
  - Biographical accounts for Allen Tupper True, 1959, undated (Box 1, Reel 4891)
  - Passports (4), 1923-1950 (Box 1, Reel 4891)
  - School papers, 1895-1899 (Box 1, Reel 4891)
  - Award medal for horsemanship, 1909 (Box 1, Reel 4891)
  - Membership cards (2), 1948-1949 (Box 1, Reel 4891)
  - Copies of True's will, 1926-1951 (Box 1, Reel 4891)
- Subject Files, 1873-1955; Series 2; (box 1, 16 folders)
  This series includes letters, journals and autobiographical accounts, notes, ephemera, printed material, and legal documents such as mining and stock certificates and wills, concerning members of the True family and organizations with which they were associated.
  Files relating to Margaret Allen Tupper True contain: an undated journal written by Margaret Tupper True's mother, Ellen Smith Tupper (transcript precedes handwritten journal); receipts for purchase of land, 1879-1892; and a diary, 1881-1888, which contains entries primarily concerning Allen Tupper True as a baby, and includes 2 photographs of True, a lock of his hair, and a cyanotype of Franklin School, El Paso, Texas. The files also contain a diary from 1891-1926, that includes entries primarily concerning Katherine Goodrich True as a baby, and includes a family tree chart; notes about the family; 4 photographs of Katherine True, 1891-1905; 1 photograph of Allen Tupper True, 1905; a composition by Katherine True; a notebook on conditions in various schools, 1907-ca. 1911; 4 real estate deeds, 1908-1913; and inheritance tax documents, 1926. The Cactus Club file contains undated miscellaneous writings by True.
  See also Series 9: Photographs, and Series 12: Artifacts.
  - Margaret Allen Tupper True (True's mother), 1873-1926; (5 folders) (Box 1, Reel 4891)
  - Henry Alphonso True (True's father), 1883-1925; (2 folders) (Box 1, Reel 4891)
  - Ira Goodrich True (True's uncle), 1904-1914 (Box 1, Reel 4891)
  - James Polk True (True's uncle), undated (Box 1, Reel 4891)
  - Mary Josephine True (True's aunt), 1888-1918 (Box 1, Reel 4891)
  - Eliza Tupper Wilkes (True's aunt), 1879-1917 (Box 1, Reel 4891)
  - James Beaman True (True's brother), 1878-1920 (Box 1, Reel 4891)
  - American Smelting & Refining Company, 1880-1916 (Box 1, Reel 4891)
  - Author's Lodge (Masons), 1908-1955 (Box 1, Reel 4891)
  - Cactus Club, 1929-1947 (Box 1, Reel 4891)
  - Central City Opera House Association, Colorado, 1933-1948 (Box 1, Reel 4891)
- Correspondence, 1841-1956; Series 3; (boxes 1-4, 3.5 linear ft.)
  Arrangement note
  This series is organized into two subseries:
  3.1: Correspondence Between Family Members, 1841-1955
  3.2: Correspondence With Business Associates, Colleagues, and Friends, 1902-1956
  - Correspondence Between Family Members, 1841-1955; 3.1
    This subseries documents True's thoughts concerning his career and the interaction among members of the True family. Various individuals discuss Tupper and True family business and events. Allen Tupper True describes his art classes at the Corcoran Gallery School, 1901-1902, Howard Pyle's class, 1902-1904, which included George Harding, Gordon McCouch, Thornton Oakley, and N. C. Wyeth, and his work with Frank Brangwyn in 1914. True also discusses his travels and projects.
    The following letters contain photographs: 04 Nov 1901 (1 photo of Harry True, Jr.); 08 Dec 1901 (13 photos of family members); May 1902 (1 cyanotype of Pyle's class); 27 Jun 1902 (1 photo of True in front of the U.S. Capitol); 22 Feb 1914 (1 photo of True and his work in his studio and 1 photo of Murphy in True's studio); 30 May 1914 (1 photo of the Robinsons' home); 09 Jun 1914 (1 photo of the Orchestre Louis Berki); 30 Jan 1915 (1 panorama photo of the Panama-Pacific Exposition); 26 Mar 1915 (1 photo of Peggie); 07 Aug 1924 (5 photos of family in an orchard)
    The files are arranged chronologically.
    - Correspondence between family members, 1841-1888, undated; (11 folders) (Box 1, Reel 4891)
    - Correspondence between family members, 1888-1900; (6 folders) (Box 1, Reel 4892)
    - Correspondence Between Family Members, 1901-Nov. 1913; (58 folders) (Box 2, Reel 4892)
    - Correspondence between Family Members, Nov. 1913-Jan. 1914; (6 folders) (Box 2, Reel 4893)
    - Correspondence between Family Members, Feb. 1914-May 1935; (61 folders) (Box 3, Reel 4893)
    - Correspondence Between Family Members, May 1935-1955; (37 folders) (Box 4, Reel 4894)
  - Correspondence With Business Associates, Colleagues, and Friends, 1902-1956; 3.2
    This subseries focuses more directly on the events of True's career. Fourteen illustrated letters from True to his wife and daughter can also be found here. Notable correspondents are listed below.
    Blashfield, Edwin: 25 Sep 1924 letter to Frank Brangwyn
    Borglum, Gutzon: 12 Mar 1936, 07 Apr 1936, 20 Feb 1937, 01 Mar 1937, 05 Jul 1937 (with autographed photo of Mount Rushmore under construction)
    Brangwyn, Frank: [Jan 1913], 26 Jan 1913, 30 Mar 1913, 08 Jun 1913, 03 Aug 1913, 29 Aug 1915, 20 Nov 1916, 17 Feb 1920, 2 illustrated letters, 1920? (with transcripts), 30 Sep [1920?], 07 May 1922 (with transcript), 22 Oct 1922 (illustrated letter with transcript), 06 May 1923 (illustrated letter with transcript), 1923? (with transcript), an illustrated letter, 1923? (with transcript), 26 Sep 1924 (with transcript), 18 Jun 1933, [1933], 05 Apr 1936 (with transcript). Also see references to Brangwyn in True's letters to his family and in Blashfield's letter to Brangwyn; see True's notebook on Brangwyn in Series "Notes"; see a print by Brangwyn under "Artworks"; and see photographs of Brangwyn and his works under "Photographs"]
    Brousse-Jacobson, Oscar: 29 Sep 1913, 1 Dec 1915
    Bruce, Edward: 18 Aug 1934
    Cook, James H.:27 Aug 1924 letter to John G. Neihardt
    Cornwell, Dean: 04 June 1932 (illustrated letter), 10 Apr 1954
    Guerin, Jules: Jan 31, 1918
    Heye, George G.: 19 Feb 1926, 12 Mar 1926, 07 Jul 1926
    McCouch, Gordon M: 08 Jul 1911, (09 May 1956 obituary notice) [also see "Photographs of friends"]
    Minnigerode, C. Powell: 10 Mar 1937
    Naismith, Grace: 23 Mar 1935, [16 letters, 1935?], 06 Jun 1936, 20 Jun 1935, 24 Jun 1935, [1935?], 29 Jul 1935, [2 letters, 1935?], 08 Sept [1935?], [1935?], 28 Sept 1935, [1935?], 29 Oct 1935], 17 Nov 1935, 04 Dec 1935, 16 Dec 1935, 26 Dec 1935, [3 letters, 1936?], 09 Mar 1936, [1936?], 09 Apr 1936, 16 May [1936?], 08 Jun 1936, 30 Jun 1936, 18 Oct [1936?], 01 Nov 1936, 02 Jun 1937, 15 Jun 1937, 24 Jun 1937, [1937?], 11 Jul 1937, 21 Nov 1955
    Neihardt, John G. (poet laureate of Nebraska): 28 Jun 1923, 04 Oct 1923, 05 Dec 1923, 25 Feb 1924 (with 14 reproductions of art work by True), [see letter, 27 Aug 1924, from James H. Cook to Neihardt], 5 May 1925, 26 Jun 1925, 25 Jul 1925, 16 Aug 1934
    Oakley, Thornton: 5 Jul 1933 [also see "Photographs of friends"]
    Phipps, Lawrence C. (Senator from Colorado): 04 Oct 1930
    Pyle, Howard: 18 May 1902, 25 May 1902, July 11, 1902, 06 Nov [1903], 04 Jun 1906 [also see references to Pyle's classes in True's letters to family members, including letter dated May 1902 containing a cyanotype of Pyle and his students; see additional photographs under "Photographs of friends"; and see exhibition catalog for Pyle under "Printed material"]
    Rowan, Edward: 24 Sep 1934
    Rush, Olive: undated
    Rutherford, Forest: 08 Mar 1914 letter to Rutherford from True contains a photo of True
    Thornton, Dan (Governor of Colorado): 25 Jan 1954
    Winter, Ezra: 23 Feb 1922
    Wyeth, N. C.: 06 Jan 1909 [also see "Photographs of friends" and "Album I"]
    - Correspondence With Business Associates, Colleagues, and Friends, 1901-1980, undated; (36 folders) (Box 4, Reel 4894-4895)
- Business Records, 1903-1951; Series 4; (box 4, 4 folder)
  This series consists of stocks and a deed for Colorado real estate, miscellaneous receipts, insurance policies, and a studio lease and inventory.
  - Stocks and deed for Colorado real estate, 1903-1942 (Box 4, Reel 4895)
  - Receipts for miscellaneous goods and hotels, 1904-1946 (Box 4, Reel 4895)
  - Insurance policies, 1933-1949 (Box 4, Reel 4895)
  - Studio lease and inventory, 1951 (Box 4, Reel 4895)
- Notes, 1902-1920; Series 5; (box 5, 10 folders)
  This series include an address book, lists of art work, and seven notebooks documenting travel, work with Frank Brangwyn, and a record of mural work, and notes on technique. The travel journal include sketches and drawings.
  - Address book, undated (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Chemistry notebook, undated (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - "Notes in the Field" and notebook containing miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Notebook containing thoughts and observations on travel to England, undated (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Notebook Cover, 1902-1915 (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Notebook containing thoughts and observations on Frank Brangwyn, 1902-1915 (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Notebook containing miscellaneous thoughts and observations, 1904-1908 (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Notebook containing a record of murals and notes on techniques, 1920 (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Lists of works, undated (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 5, Reel 4895)
- Writings, 1896-1926; Series 6; (box 5, 5 folders)
  Material in this series consists of childhood writings, miscellaneous writings by True, and poems.
  - Miscellaneous childhood writings, 1896-1899 (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - "The Mountain Pony" by Allen Tupper True, 1906 (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Miscellaneous writings by True, 1906-ca. 1910 (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Essay by True on article from the Museum Journal, "Another Fresco from Moon Hill Monastery" by Helen Fernald, 1926 (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Poems, undated (Box 5, Reel 4895)
- Artwork, 1897-1923; Series 7; (boxes 5, 10 and OV folder, 0.5 linear ft.)
  This series consists of a sketchbook, cartoons and caricatures, sketches and drawings, paintings on cardboard, designs based on Native American pottery and artifacts, designs for murals in Denver Civic Center, the Colorado State Capitol, the U.S. National Bank building, Boulder Dam, and the Voorhies Memorial Arch in Denver. There are also original Christmas cards, illustrated letters in the Correspondence Series, an illustrated travel journal, a print by Frank Brangwyn, and miscellaneous art work by others.
  - Sketchbook, undated (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Cartoons and caricatures (13), 1897-1898 (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Drawings (6) (see also sol box 10 ), undated (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Paintings (2) (see also ov folder), 1908; (2 folders) (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Designs based on Native American pottery (54) (see also sol box 10), undated; (5 folders) (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Designs based on Native American artifacts (25) (see also sol box 10), 1923 (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Art work for Christmas cards (6 drawings), 1913-1921 (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Art work by Frank Brangwyn (1 print), undated (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Miscellaneous art work by others, undated (Box 5, Reel 4895)
- Project Files, 1912-1987; Series 8; (box 5, 0.75 linear ft.)
  This series contains letters, legal documents, printed material, and photographs concerning True's mural projects for the state capitol buildings of Colorado, Missouri, Nebraska, and Wyoming.
  True acted as color consultant for the Bureau of Reclamation on Bouder Dam and Grand Coulee Dam (Washington State) and during the construction of several other dams and their power houses, including Bonneville (Oregon), Shasta (California), Friant (California), and Minidoka (Idaho)]. His consultation work on these projects is also documented here.
  Files typically contain any or all of the following types of material: photographs of the installed murals; related letters, contracts, copyright cards and purchase orders; illustrated notebooks, sketches, and paintings; schematic drawings; and printed material.
  - Unidentified mural, undated (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Colorado Psychopathic Hospital, undated (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Graland School, undated (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Waring Residence, undated (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Anne Evans House, Mural "Free Trappers,", 1912 (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Dickinson Branch Library, Denver, Colorado, Murals: "Miners," "Trappers," and "Pioneers,", 1912-1913 (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Warren Branch Library, Denver, Colorado, Mural: "Commerce of the Prairies,", 1913 (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Panama-Pacific International Exposition, San Francisco, California, Union Oil Panorama, 1914-1915 (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Utah State Capitol, Salt Lake City, Utah, 1915-1919 (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Denver Public Library, Civic Center, Denver, Colorado, Murals: "Cliff Dwellers" and "Hopi Potter,", 1916 (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Union Station, Denver, Colorado, 1916-1917 (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - America Theatre, Denver, Colorado, Murals: "Indians" and "Trappers,", 1916-1917 (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Hamilton County Court House, Cincinnati, Ohio, 1916-1918 (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Wyoming State Capitol, Cheyenne, Wyoming, Murals: "Frontier Cavalry Officer" ("The Soldier"), "Railroad Builders, Surveyors," "Pony Express Rider," "Indian Chief Cheyenne," "Stagecoach," "Cattlemen," "Trappers,", 1917-1918; (includes 1 illustrated notebook) (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Montana National Bank, Billings, Montana, Mural: "The Buffalo Hunter,", 1918; (includes 1 schematic drawing of location of murals) (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Missouri State Capitol, Jefferson City, Missouri, Murals include: "Aborigines," "Buffalo Hunter," "Early Rivermen," "Free Trapper," "Missionary Explorers," "Pioneer Mother," "Railroad Builder," "A River Pilot," and "Spanish Governors,", 1919-1925 (Box 5, Reel 4895)
    (3 folders; includes 6 sketches, 1 photograph of a stagecoach carrying African-American soldiers, 5 photographs of riverboats, and 19 photographs of True and his murals)
  - Greek Theatre and Voories Memorial, Civic Center, Denver, Colorado, Murals: "The Trapper," "The Prospector," and "Bison,", 1919-1925 (Box 5, Reel 4895)
    (contains 1 schematic drawing of location of murals, and 2 oversize paintings of Bisons)
  - Criminal Court Building, Denver, Colorado, 1920 (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Morey Junior High School, Denver, Colorado, 1920-1921 (Box 5, Reel 4895)
  - Nebraska State Capitol, Lincoln, Nebraska (see also sol box 10), 1921-1954 (Box 5, Reel 4895)
    (3 folders; includes 1 blueprint for location of murals, 2 sketches, and a schematic drawing of location of murals)
  - Colorado National Bank, Denver, Colorado, Mural: "Indian Memories" (see also sol box 10), 1921-1987 (Box 5, Reel 4896)
  - Taylor Day Nursery, Colorado Springs, Colorado, 1922-1923 (Box 5, Reel 4896)
  - Colorado Springs Day Nursery, Colorado Springs, Colorado, 1924 (Box 5, Reel 4896)
  - Colorado State Capitol, Denver, Colorado (see also sol box 10), 1924-1940; (2 folders; includes 18 sketches) (Box 5, Reel 4896)
  - Cosmopolitan Hotel, Denver, Colorado, 1925-1926 (Box 5, Reel 4896)
  - U.S. National Bank Building, Denver, Colorado, 1925-1933 (Box 5, Reel 4896)
  - Washington State Capitol, Olympia, Washington (see also sol box 10), 1925-1948; (includes 1 blueprint) (Box 5, Reel 4896)
  - Mountain States Telephone and Telegraph Company Building, Denver, Colorado, Murals include: "Primitive Communication--The Smoke Signal," "Pioneer Communication--The Pony Express," "Mountain Construction," "The Crucible of Science," "The Wings of Thought," and "The Spirit of Service" (see also sol box 10), 1927-1929; (5 folders) (Box 5, Reel 4896)
  - Ingersoll Residence, Colorado Springs, Colorado, 1930 (Box 5, Reel 4896)
  - North Dakota State Capitol, Bismarck, North Dakota, 1931-1932 (Box 5, Reel 4896)
  - City and County Building, Denver, Colorado, 1931-1950 (Box 5, Reel 4896)
  - Colorado Room, Century of Progress Exposition, Chicago, Illinois, 1933 (Box 5, Reel 4896)
  - Boulder Dam Power Plant, Nevada-Arizona State Line (see also sol box 10 and project file for Bureau of Reclamation, Department of the Interior), 1934-1938; (6 folders; includes 1 illustrated notebook) (Box 5, Reel 4896)
  - Golden Gate International Exposition, San Francisco, California, 1936 (Box 5, Reel 4896)
  - Brown Palace Hotel, Denver, Colorado, 1936-1937 (Box 5, Reel 4896)
  - Bureau of Reclamation, Department of the Interior, Washington, D.C. (see project file for Boulder Dam Power Plant), 1940-1945; (8 folders) (Box 5, Reel 4896)
  - Colorado University Student Union, Boulder, Colorado, 1943-1953 (Box 5, Reel 4896)
- Photographs, 1859-1950; Series 9; (boxes 6-7, 1.5 linear ft.)
  This series includes photographs of True, his studios, his works, True family members, friends, residences, and reference photographs of Native Americans, cowboys, settlers, and other Western subjects.
  Photographs of True family members include Minnie True; Hattie Cherry (sister of Henry True) and Susie Cherry; Ira Goodrich True; Margaret True Thompson; Diemer True; Leland True; and Jamie True and his grandmother Mrs. Beyer. There is also a tintype of 2 unidentified children.
  Photographs of the Tupper family include Noah and Hannah Wheaton Smith (grandparents of Margaret Tupper True); Ellen Smith Tupper; Holmes Tupper; Lucille Tupper; Mila Tupper; Madge Tupper; Kate Tupper Galfin; Wilhelmina Wilkes; and William F. Wilkes (husband of Eliza Tupper Wilkes)
  Photographs of Allen Tupper True and family members include True as an infant; True and his siblings; True as an adult including 1 cyanotype;True and his children; Hans Mueller (Jane's husband); and miscellaneous family members.
  The two photograph albums found here show True, his friends, his studio, N.C. Wyeth and True at the easel in his studio, and various outdoor scenes.
  See also Series 13: Glass Negatives
  - Photographs of True family members, 1862-ca. 1900 (Box 6, Reel 4896)
  - Photographs of Tupper family members, 1888-1889 (Box 6, Reel 4896)
  - Photographs of Henry True and Margaret Tupper True, 1880-1890 (Box 6, Reel 4896)
  - Photographs of Allen Tupper True and family members, 1881-1950; (7 folders) (Box 6, Reel 4897)
  - Photographs of True and his various studios (51), undated (Box 6, Reel 4897)
  - Photographs of Howard Pyle's studio and classes, ca. 1902 (Box 6, Reel 4897)
    (14 photographs including 1 cyanotype of: George Harding, Gordon M. McCouch, Thornton Oakley, Howard Pyle, Allen Tupper True, and N.C. Wyeth)
  - Photograph of Frank Brangwyn and William Merritt Chase in London and photograph of Brangwyn's studio, 1914, undated (Box 6, Reel 4897)
  - Photographs of family friends, 1859-1933 (Box 6, Reel 4897)
  - Miscellaneous Friends, undated (Box 6, Reel 4897)
  - 10 Photographs of Victoria Kirby, undated, 1964 (Box 6, Reel 4897)
  - Terry the Dog, undated (Box 6, Reel 4897)
  - 5 Photographs of family residences, undated (Box 6, Reel 4897)
  - 6 Photographs of family places of business, ca. 1880-1894 (Box 6, Reel 4897)